The Rise and Fall of a Real Life Mafia Don
Gotti is a crime, drama, tv movie film directed by Robert Harmon.
John Gotti, the head of a small New York mafia crew
breaks a few of the old family rules.
He rises to become the head of the Gambino family and the
most well-known mafia boss in America.
Life is good, but suspicion creeps in, and greed, rule-breaking and
his high public profile all threaten to topple him.
John Gotti, played by Armand Assante.
Sammy Gravano, played by William Forsythe.
Robert DiBernardo, played by Frank Vincent.
Angelo Ruggiero, played by Vincent Pastore.
Neil Dellacroce, played by Anthony Quinn.
Paul Castellano, played by Richard C. Sarafian.
Gotti is a 1996 American crime drama television film directed
by Robert Harmon and written by Steve Shagan.
Based primarily on the columns of reporter Jerry Capeci, who also co-wrote the 1996 non-fiction book Gotti: Rise and Fall with Gene Mustain and served as the film's executive
producer, the film stars Armand Assante in the title role as infamous Gambino crime family boss John Gotti, along with William Forsythe, and Anthony Quinn.
It premiered on HBO on August 17, 1996.
Assante won the Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Lead Actor
in a Miniseries or a Special for his performance.
Assante received nominations for the Golden Globe Award for Best Actor in a Miniseries or Motion Picture Made for Television and the
Screen Actors Guild Award for Outstanding Performance by a Male Actor in a Miniseries or Television Movie the same year.
The film explores themes of new york city, crime
boss, biography, based on true story.
The tone is emotional.